Ambrose Wilkinson

email: ambrose.wilkins@gmail.com tel: 207.451.5536

New York, NY 10024

Portfolio: a-breezy.github.io/portolio

GitHub: github.com/a-breezy | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/ambrose-wilkinson

Summary

Full-Stack Web Developer with keen interest in learning and developing on Web3 and Software Engineering. Recently received certificate in MERN stack development from Columbia University, Fu Foundation School of Engineering. A lifelong learner with past experience in Michelin-Starred New York City restaurants, which have led to a personable, friendly demeanor as well as leadership skills and quick thinking.

Technical Skills

Development Skills: Git, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Express.js, SQL, Node.js, MongoDB, Mongoose ODM, React.js, GraphQL, Apollo Graph Platform

Projects

Let's Eat | Repo: github.com/a-breezy/LetsEat | Deployed: a-breezy.github.io/LetsEat/ Restaurant randomizer to choose a restaurant for users based on their location using the Yelp API

- Technologies: HTML, CSS, Bulma, JavaScript, jQuery, Polyfill.io, Moment.js
- Role: Front-End JavaScript logic, led team discussions, and managed deadlines

Save the Steer || Repo: github.com/a-breezy/save-the-steer || Deployed: quiet-river-39422.herokuapp.com/ A progressive web app to track you budget regardless of internet connectivity

- Technologies: JavaScript, Express.js, Node.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, compression, morgan
- Role: Created Back-End and refactored the code to make into a PWA

Kitchen Sink | Repo: github.com/antger78/kitchen_sink | Deployed: kitchen-sink.herokuapp.com/ User generated recipe app to figure out what to cook when you need help cooking

- Technologies: JavaScript, Express.js, Apollo/GraphQL, bcrypt, Bootstrap, React, React Bootstrap, JSON Web Token, React Router
- Role: Created Mongoose models, styled CSS, and facilitated group meetings

Experience

Contra: New York City, USA

May 2021 - Mar 2022

Michelin-Starred: Bartender and Server

- Composed cocktail list that highlighted the restaurant's food menu as well as local, seasonal ingredients
- Dedicated to serving high-profile guests, creating a great experience, and being a team player

An Undefined Journey: New York City, USA

Nov 2018 - Sept 2021

Founder, Photographer, and Content Creator

- Designed a minimalist portfolio and travel journal using Elementor
- Authored posts that included photography to paint a rich picture of what travel to certain places was like
- Improved social media following by posting daily, which increased viewership by 70%

Faro: New York City, USA

Aug 2017 – Jan 2018

Michelin-Starred: Lead Server and Bartender

- Contributed to the team by learning all front of house roles and filling in where needed
- Consistently upsold menu items and dining experiences to create a better experience for the patrons
- Partnered with the Chef to run an exclusive 8 seat, 8 course tasting menu twice a week

Education

Columbia Fu Foundation School of Engineering, NYC, USA Certificate in MERN Full Stack Development

Sept 2021 — Mar 2022

CUNY Hunter College, NYC, USA Bachelor of Arts in Creative Writing and Sociology

Jan 2012 — Jan 2016 GPA: 3.7/4.0

Graduated with Special Honors